Going back to the question I asked earlier,
再回到刚刚问的问题上
based on whether the gain coefficient and
你能根据利得系数
the accelerate coefficient are positive or negative,
和加速系数为正还是为负
can you decide which scenarios we would rather go long or short?
判断在哪种情形下做多或做空吗？
We'll take a look at how the coefficients of
下面看看如何根据
the stock price approximation formula can inform
股价逼近公式的系数
our decision as to which stock we should go long or short.
判断做多或做空哪支股票
This in turn allows us to create an alpha factor based on these two coefficients.
我们将根据这两个系数创建一个 alpha 因子
Let's take an example of two stocks, A and B.
假设有两支股票 A 和 B
Stock A has a gain coefficient of 10 and an accelerate coefficient of two.
股票 A 的利得系数为 10 加速系数为 2
Stock B also has a gain coefficient of 10 and accelerate coefficient of negative two.
股票 B 的利得系数也为 10 加速系数为 -2
If you were going long both stocks,
如果要做多两支股票
which one would you put more weight on?
哪支股票权重更高？
Since stock A has the trajectory of an accelerated gain,
因为股票 A 的轨迹是加速利得
whereas stock B looks like a decelerated gain,
而股票 B 是减速利得
we would put a larger long wait on stock A, the accelerated gain.
所以我们将为股票 A 分配更大的做多权重 即加速利得
Let's look at another example with two downward trending stocks.
再举个例子 假设有两支下降趋势的股票
Let's say stock C has a gain coefficient of negative
股票 C 的利得系数为 -10
10 and accelerate coefficient of two.
加速系数为 2
Stock D has a gain coefficient of negative 10,
股票 D 的利得系数为 -10
as well as an accelerate coefficient of negative two.
加速系数为 -2
If you were to go short both stocks,
如果要做空这两支股票
which one would you put a larger short position on?
哪支股票的做空权重更大？
In this case, stock C has the trajectory of a decelerated loss,
股票 C 的轨迹是减速损失
and stock D has the look of an accelerated loss.
股票 D 的轨迹是加速损失
So, you'd prefer to put a larger shortwave on stock D, the accelerated loss.
所以为股票 D 分配更大的做空权重 即加速损失
Now, you may have noticed something interesting with
你可能从利得和加速系数上
the signs of the gain and the accelerate coefficients.
注意到了一些有趣的现象
When the product of gain times accelerate is positive and large,
当利得系数乘以加速系数的积是很大的正数时
the signal generally means to take a larger long position.
通常表明采取更大的做多头寸
When both are negative,
当二者都为负时
the signal means to take a larger short position.
表明应采取更大的做空头寸
If we were to convert the gain and accelerate coefficients
如果将利得和加速系数
into ranks then multiply them together,
转换为排名 然后相乘
the product of the gain times accelerate would represent an alpha factor.
利得乘以加速的积表示 alpha 因子
When the rank of gain and the rank of accelerate are both small,
如果利得排名和加速排名都很小
the product is small,
那么积很小
and this is a signal to take a larger short position.
表明应采取更大的做空头寸
If the rank of gain and the rank of accelerate are both large,
如果利得排名和加速排名都很大
then the product is also large,
那么积也很大
and this is a signal to take a larger long wait.
表明应分配更大的做多权重
This is our first conditional factor.
这就是我们的第一个条件因子
The key idea is that when you see and think conditional.
关键在于 当你看到“AND”时 看做条件因子
Here, we have momentum and convexity.
在此例中是动量和凸性
So, to summarize, we can use
总结下 我们可以使用多元回归
a multiple regression where the independent variables are time and time squared,
其中自变量是时间 t 和 t^2
and the dependent variable is the stock price.
因变量是股价
This regression gives us estimates for the coefficients gain and accelerate.
这个回归可以告诉我们利得和加速系数的估算值
We create our factor by first converting gain and accelerate into ranks,
我们首先将利得和加速系数转换为排名
and then multiplying the ranks together to create a joint factor.
然后将排名相乘 得出联合因子